



🔀 up209d@gmail.com

up.damgteam.com

Unit 2307, 11 Rose Lane, Melbourne, VIC, 3000

INTRODUCTION

DOB: 20th September 1987 | Nationality: Vietnamese

I have lived in Victoria for 4 years since the first time I came to Australia, and I prefer living here rather anywhere in Australia. I finished my study at Monash University, got a job, a lot of good friends and workmates. Today, I would like to have a peaceful life on this land for my career and my future.

My career goal is to be a well-rounded front-end developer. I keep myself up to date with the most recent technologies of the industry, share my experience to communities and learn from other developers all over the world. Along with making UI components for a website, software and mobile application, my job is also about data visualizing, 2D/3D interactive & abstract presentation so-called creative coding. Creative coding can be archived in any developing environment. With years of experience in web industry, thus, I prefer creative coding in this area. For that way, I can balance between illustration idea and programming. It is so interesting that what you made in static design turned into live by the art of math and logic underneath your coding lines.

EDUCATION

2005 - 2009

Bachelor of Computer Sciences - Information Technology

> Vietnam National Economics University

2009 - 2012

Diploma of Digital Animation & Motion Graphics

> Vietnam FPT University

2014 - 2016

Master of Multimedia

> Monash University

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS







∑® up209d@gmail.com

up.damgteam.com

Unit 2307, 11 Rose Lane, Melbourne, VIC, 3000

SKILL PROFILE

FRONT-END DEVELOPING

I divide my frond-end approaches into 2 stacks:

- > AngularJS+UI-Router+Boostrap: I started this stack from the beginning of my front-end journey in combination with Gulp as project packaging. It is still my farvorite SPA developing stack for its convenience of project setup and widely supported by front-end community.
- > React + React Router + Redux + Material UI: This stack is my sword in front-end developing industry, particularly with the support from NodeJS server and ExpressJs, it can be easily to achieve server-side rendering. I am capable for setup vanilla project boilerplate from scratch with manual Webpack configuration as well as from instant-toolkit such as React-create-app or framework like NextJs.

CREATIVE CODING

Creative coding is not only my job but also my hobby. Doing experiments on wide variety of javascript libraries is what I often do in my leisure time.

- > D3/GreenSock: I use D3 for developing charts & graphs, SVG manipulation and controlling time-based tween transitions. In project without charts & graphs, I would consider GreenSock or other dedicated timeline managing libraries such as AnimeJs or PopMotion. All of them can be used in combination with Canvas Renderer and WebGL Renderer to create amazing animations.
- > PixiJs/ThreeJs/WebGL: PixiJs is my top choice of 2D WebGL Renderer while ThreeJs is absolutely the way to go with 3D WebGL Renderer. Particurlaly, both libraries is capable to make custom shaders which are written in native WebGL (GLSL) language in order to maximize the usage of GPU and minimize the work-load burden from CPU thus, significantly improve graphic performance.
- > Others: There are still a tons of amazing libraries and toolkits from genius developers out there. They are worth to learn and I got experiments on some of them. For example: Matter.js A Js physic simulation, Paper.js a vector graphic manipulating library, P5.js/Processing a great source of learning maths and creative coding strategies, and vvvv a productive toolkit for creative coding.

BACK-END DEVELOPING

Being a front-end developer, I am aware of that I need to know about back-end developing since the mixing area between front-end and back-end is significant. In addition, some techniques cannot be archived by client-side only but must be implemented from a server environment.

- > PHP/MySQL: I have started using PHP and MySQL to make RESTful API for AJAX calling since a dissertation of my I.T Bachelor in 2009. Thesedays, I am still using it with my AngularJs stack for many clients who do not require the new NodeJs server but traditional NGINX/Apache server.
- > NodeJs + ExpressJs + MongoDB/Firebase: In combination with my React stack, the outcome (MERN Stack) is the most modern and universal web developing solution at the moment. MERN Stack is a game change of my career and I would prefer using this developing eco-system in all of my next coming projects.

OTHER ADDITIONAL SKILLS

I am flexible based on the work requirements, I find myself obtaining additional skills such as **HighChart** - an instant solutions of charts on web, **Google Map API + Leaflet** - vital map providers and controllers. I am also suitable for design works with **Adobe Creative Suite** (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign & After Effect).





™ up209d@gmail.com

up.damgteam.com

Unit 2307, 11 Rose Lane, Melbourne, VIC, 3000

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

4+ Years Experience

DATA ARTS PTY LTD.

8/95 Victoria Street, Fitzroy, Victoria, 3065 | info@datalabsagency.com | 03 9416 3033

From 1st June 2017 to 1st July 2018 to Now

Position: Full-time Front-end Developer & Data Visualizer

Developing: I am a main developer in Data Arts web-app projects from July 2017 til now.

Public Projects:

Dep. of Education & Training - School Funding Estimator https://www.education.gov.au/school-funding-estimator/

Datalabs - Queensland Wildlife:

https://demos.datalabsagency.com/qld/

Datalabs - Introduction to Data Visualization:

http://aws.datalabs.com.au/

Obikus - Interactive Chain Map:

https://demos.orbikus.com/orbikus_interactive_chain_map

SEEK - Laws of Attraction (AU/NZ):

https://insightsresources.seek.com.au/page/data-lab

Melbourne University Research Events Map:

http://benews.unimelb.edu.au/

Private Projects Clients:

Transport for Victoria | Australasian Fleet Management Association (AfMA) | Transurban Ltd. | Turnstile Group

Duties:

- Data Visualization developing: D3/HighChart + GreenSock/PixiJS.
- Map Visualization developing: Leaflet/Google Map/MapBox.
- 3D Data Visualization developing: ThreeJs + Native WebGL (GLSL).
- Front-end developing: AngularJs 1.x + UI-Router + Bootstrap 4.
- Front-end developing: React + React-Router + Redux (Thunk/Saga) + Material-UI + React-Motion.
- Project packaging development and production with Webpack/Gulp.
- Back-end developing: Nodejs + ExpressJs + Document-based databases (MongoDB/Firebase).
- Back-end developing: Apache/NGINX PHP + MySQL.
- > **Project Version Control**: I take full responsibility for Data Arts private projects' source code from Git Services (GitHub & Bitbucket).
- > DataArts Domains & Servers: I take care of company's domains and clients' domains, assign SSL Certificates on them, managing Data Arts Servers (NodeJs Server on AWS EC2 Ubuntu, NGINX Server on Liquid Web Hosting via CPanel & WHM).

A GAP IN MY CAREER

From 1st May 2014 to 30th May 2017

Studied at Monash University

I focused on study in order to get a good academic record at Monash University. I found that doing freelancer job take too much time so I couldn't focus on my self-projects at Monash. I decided to temporarily quit the freelance offers. After graduate, I spent few months resting and travelling. It also took me other months updating my knowledge and building my portfolio online which is now at https://up.damgteam.com.

Self-Projects at Monash University

Australian Open Tennis - History (TouchScreen Version) https://up209d.github.io/OpenTheFirst/ Night Owl vs Early Bird - Interactive Web Illustration https://up209d.github.io/LastAssignment/project/





up209d@gmail.com

up.damgteam.com

Unit 2307, 11 Rose Lane, Melbourne, VIC, 3000

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

4+ Years Experience

CMC TELECOM

11th floor, CMC Tower, 11 Duy Tan, Dich Vong Hau Ward, Cau Giay District, Hanoi, Vietnam | info@cmctelecom.vn | Tel +84 1900 2020

From 3rd April 2012 to 24th April 2013

Position: Full-time Web/iOS Developer & Designer

- **Developing**: I was a main developer for website development in CMC Telecom, and partly for UI Development in IOS application development (Objective C).
 - Developed web game interface for GameXanh, an online card games project.
 - Developed front-end part for Life4U project an e-wallet service including website & mobile applications.
 - Developed website for SMSViet a SMS Branding Service with WordPress CMS with custom template & plugins.
 - Developed iOS UI part of an application for managing documentation of General Department of Taxation
 - Developed web-based interactivity advertisements (HTML Canvas, Flash).
 - Managed and maintained MySQL databases for GameXanh, Life4U & SMSViet.
 - Programmed with PHP, ASP, Objective C, JavaScript (Jquery, Underscore & AngularJs), HTML5 & CSS.

W.G CO. LTD

Unit 1503 - C37 Bac Ha Building - To Huu - Thanh Xuan District Hanoi, Vietnam | info@wecan-group.com | Tel +84 24 6664 0261 / +84 24 6285 2660

From 1st August 2009 to 1st February 2012 | From 1st May 2012 to 1st March 2014

Position: Freelancer Front-end Developer

- > **Developing**: I took responsibility for front-end part of **~100 website projects** in W.G such as information websites, ecommerce online shopping websites and partly did website design also.
 - Converted design from PSD to PHP, HTML, Javascript & CSS.
 - Developed custom UI Templates (PHP) for W.G Commercial CMS.
 - Test and debug front-end part for browsers compatibility (IE 6,7,8,9,10,11, Mozilla Firefox, Google Chrome).
 - Integrated AJAX techniques (Jauery AJAX) in client-side to communicate with W.G Commercial CMS.
 - Developed PHP RESTful API for AJAX JSON Data fetching from W.G Commercial CMS Database.
 - Developed interactive banners, slideshows, photo galleries, carousel sliders by Javascript & HTML Canvas renderer.

REFERENCES

DATA ARTS PTY LTD.

Domenic Brooks Associate Director Tel: 0421 385 709

Email: dom@datalabsagency.com

Otto Ottinger Managing Director Tel: 0458 858 825

Email: otto@datalabsagency.com

W.G CO. LTD

Nam Duc Nguyen
Associate Director
Tel: +84 984 466 909

Email: namnd@wecan-group.com

Cuong Cao Hoang Managing Director Tel: +84 936 293 789

Email: cuonghc@wecan-group.com

CMC TELECOM

Hieu Bao Pham
Project Manager
Tel: +84 984 899 996
Email: phambaohieu@gmail.com